Guide to the Douglas C. Kimmel papers, 1970-2009.
Kimmel, Douglas C. papers,
Division of Rare and Manuscript Collections, Cornell University Library
Douglas C. Kimmel papers, 1970-2009.
7843
Douglas C. Kimmel
1 cubic foot.
Publications.
Division of Rare and Manuscript Collections, Cornell University Library
Versions of Kimmel's professional writing, including an abstract of his 1970 dissertation though "Gerodiversity and Social Justice: Voices of Minority Elders," a paper presented at the 2009 Multicultural Conference and Summit in New Orleans. His work addresses health issues of LGBT populations in rural communities, HIV testing and safer sex practices, ageism, racism and homophobia, gay and bisexual Asian and African-American men, and other aspects of providing mental and other health care to LGBT populations over their lifespan.
BIOGRAPHICAL NOTE
Douglas C. Kimmel trained in clinical psychology at the University of Colorado (B. A., 1965) and the University of Chicago (A. M., 1969, Ph.D., 1970) and taught at City College, City University of New York, 1970-1999, with three visiting professorships in Tokyo, Japan. He published on the topics of adolescence, aging, and gender identity and sexual orientation and gave distinguished service to the psychology profession and the LGBT community over five decades. In 1977, he co-founded Services and Advocacy for GLBT Elders (SAGE) in New York City and became Chair of the Association of Lesbian and Gay Psychologists. From 2006-2013, he served as Editor, Society for the Psychological Study of Lesbian, Gay, Bisexual, and Transgender Issues: Division 44 of the American Psychological Association Newsletter. He continues to serve as historian of Division 44. In the years post-2000, his awards include: Community Service Award, Maine Lesbian Gay Political Alliance Foundation, 2003; Distinguished Service Award, Society for the Psychological Study of Lesbian and Gay Issues: Division 44 of the American Psychological Association, 2008; and the Distinguished Elder Award, American Psychological Association Presidential Citation, presented at the National Multicultural Conference and Summit, 2011.
COLLECTION DESCRIPTION
Versions of Kimmel's professional writing, including an abstract of his 1970 dissertation though "Gerodiversity and Social Justice: Voices of Minority Elders," a paper presented at the 2009 Multicultural Conference and Summit in New Orleans. His work addresses health issues of LGBT populations in rural communities, HIV testing and safer sex practices, ageism, racism and homophobia, gay and bisexual Asian and African-American men, and other aspects of providing mental and other health care to LGBT populations over their lifespan.
SUBJECTS
Names:
Kimmel, Douglas C.
Subjects:
Adolescence.; Aging.; African American gays.; Asian American gays.; Bisexuality.; Gay men.; HIV.; Homosexuality.; Lesbianism.; Mental health.; Safe sex in AIDS prevention.; Transsexuals.
INFORMATION FOR USERS
CONTAINER LIST
- Adult Development: Challenges for Counseling, 1976 (Box 1, Folder 2)
- Kimmel / Adult Development: Implications for Aging, 1975 (Box 1, Folder 3)
- Adult Development and Aging: A Gay Perspective / (Journal of Social Issues), 1978 (Box 1, Folder 4)
- Adolescence in the US and Thoughts About Japan, 1987-05 (Box 1, Folder 5)
- African-American Gay and Bisexual Men at Midlife (SAGE Conference), 2000 (Box 1, Folder 6)
- Ageism, Psychology and Public Policy (American Psychologist), 1988 (Box 1, Folder 7)
- Aging and Families: A Lesbian and Gay Perspective (APA), 1994 (Box 1, Folder 8)
- Ageism and Implications for Sexual Orientation, 2002-08-23 (Box 1, Folder 9)
- Aging and Sexual Orientation, 2002 (Box 1, Folder 10)
- Aging Amnong the Giants: Aging in the US and Japan, 1987-05 (Box 1, Folder 11)
- Aging, Diversity, and Difference in Rural Perspective, 2015 (Box 1, Folder 12)
- Aging in the US and Japan CUNY (Kaleidoscope), 1989 (Box 1, Folder 13)
- Avoiding Heterosexist Bias (American Psychologist), 1991 (Box 1, Folder 14)
- Characteristics of GLB Asians (Asian Americans Journal of Homosexuality), 2004 (Box 1, Folder 15)
- Christmas, Train Schedules and Community, 1995-10 (Box 1, Folder 16)
- Comments on Recognition as an Elder by NMCPS, 2011 (Box 1, Folder 17)
- Concerns About Aging Parents (Tokyo American Club Magazine), 2001 (Box 1, Folder 18)
- Combining Scholarship and Passion Ageism and Heterosexism (APA), 1991 (Box 1, Folder 19)
- Counseling Older Gay Men, 2002 (Box 1, Folder 20)
- Current Theoretical Issues in AD + A (APA), 1980 (Box 1, Folder 21)
- Ethical Issues in Gerontological Research, 1990 (Box 1, Folder 22)
- Exploring the Lives of Older African-American Gay Men, 1997 (Box 1, Folder 23)
- Factors of Marital Adjustment Kimmel and Vander Veen (Journal of Mariage and Family), 1974 (Box 1, Folder 24)
- False Normality (APA), 1987 (Box 1, Folder 25)
- The Families of Older Gay Men and Lesbians (Generations), 1992 (Box 1, Folder 26)
- Future Generations of Lesbian and Gay Issues (APA), 1990-08 (Box 1, Folder 27)
- Gay, Lesbian, Bisexual, and Transgender Aging in Maine, 2013-03 (Box 1, Folder 28)
- Gay People Actually Grow Old (Mini-White House Conference on Aging NYC), 1980 (Box 1, Folder 29)
- Gay People Grow Old Too GSA Paper Revised for Journal of Aging, 1974-07 (Box 1, Folder 30)
- Gerodiversity and Social Justice: Voices of Minority Elders, 2009 (Box 1, Folder 31)
- Growing Older in the US and Thoughts About Aging in Japan, 1995 (Box 1, Folder 32)
- Growing Older in the US… TMU Lecture Tokyo and Korea, 1995-02-08-1995-03-24 (Box 1, Folder 33)
- A History of Division 44, 1999 (Box 1, Folder 34)
- HIV Testing and Safer Sex Practice Among Gay Asian Men, 2007-08-18 (Box 1, Folder 35)
- Homophobia Entry in Encyclopedia of Applied Psychology, 2004 (Box 1, Folder 36)
- Homosexuality as a Psychiatric Diagnosis (Japanese), 1995-06 (Box 1, Folder 37)
- Homosexuality as a Psychiatric Diagnosis (Japanese and Chinese), 1995-06-1998 (Box 1, Folder 38)
- Identifying… GLBT… Rural Communities (NHRA), 2000 (Box 1, Folder 39)
- Including Sexual Orientation in Life-Span Developmental Psychology, 1998-2000 (Box 1, Folder 40)
- Dissertation Abstracts Interacting Family Components, 1970 (Box 1, Folder 41)
- Is Sexual Orientation a Meaningful Research Variable? (APA), 1983 (Box 1, Folder 42)
- Lesbian and Gay Issues" The US and Japan, 1987 (Box 1, Folder 43)
- Lesbian, Gay, Bisexual, and Transgender Aging Concerns, 2014 (Box 1, Folder 44)
- Homosexuality - Entry in Encyclopedia of Aging, 2000-01-19 (Box 1, Folder 45)
- Lesbian and Gay Male Aging (APA), 1991 (Box 1, Folder 46)
- Lesbian and Gay Male Sexuality Presentation to the Episcopal Diocese of Rhode Island, 1990-09-13 (Box 1, Folder 47)
- Lesbians and Gay Men Also Grow Old 7/93 Draft, 1995 (Box 1, Folder 48)
- Lesbians and Gay Men in Midlife, 1995 (Box 1, Folder 49)
- Lesbians and Gays Also Grow Old APA Presidential (Div. 44) Address, 1987 (Box 1, Folder 50)
- Life-History Interview of Aging Gay Men (I.J. of Aging), 1979 (Box 1, Folder 51)
- Life-History Interview of Aging Gay Men (Gerontological Society), 1976-11 (Box 1, Folder 52)
- Older African-American Gay Men/GSA, 1991-11 (Box 1, Folder 53)
- Older Lesbians and Gay Men (NGHEF Sourcebook), 1984 (Box 1, Folder 54)
- Opposing Discriminatory Legislation and Initiatives Aimed at LGB Persons, 2010-08 (Box 1, Folder 55)
- Patterns of Aging Among Gay Men (Christopher Street), 1977-11 (Box 1, Folder 56)
- Personality Ratings Based on Handwritting Analysis and Clinical Judgement, 1966 (Box 1, Folder 57)
- Practicing or Teaching About Sexual Orientation? (Contemporary Psychology), 1997 (Box 1, Folder 58)
- Pscyhological Study of Gay and Lesbian Issues - Rothstein Lecture MEPA, 1994-04-23 (Box 1, Folder 59)
- Psychotherapy and the Older Gay Man, 1977 (Box 1, Folder 60)
- Psychotherapy with Older Gay Men, 2008 (Box 1, Folder 61)
- Publishing in Emerging Areas and Data (APA), 1985 (Box 1, Folder 62)
- Reflections on Dr. Borg's Life Review, 1977 (Box 1, Folder 63)
- Relationship Initiation Development: A Life-Span Development Approach, 1979 (Box 1, Folder 64)
- Retirement Choice and Satisfaction (Journal of Gerontology), 1978 (Box 1, Folder 65)
- Retirement Timing and Satisfaction (Aging and Work), 1979 (Box 1, Folder 66)
- Retirement Style and Satisfaction (I.J. of Aging), 1981 (Box 1, Folder 67)
- Same-Sex Marriage Referendum - The Maine Example, 2010-08 (Box 1, Folder 68)
- Sexual Orientation Lecture Tokyo and Sendai, 1994-12-1995-03 (Box 1, Folder 69)
- Social Interaction Analysis of Timing and Experience, 1974 (Box 1, Folder 70)
- Symbolic Interaction Approach to Personality, 1975 (Box 1, Folder 71)
- Variations in Self-Rated Personality Personality Needs As a Function of Sex, Age and SES from Adolescence to Middle Age (APA Montreal), 1973 (Box 1, Folder 72)
- What a Light it Shed: E. Hooker, 2000 (Box 1, Folder 73)
- Book Reviews by Kimmel, 1976-04-2000 (Box 1, Folder 74)